Chadwick Boseman: Portrait of an Artist is a
documentary film directed by Awol Erizku.
An intimate look at the Oscar-nominated actor’s incomparable artistry, and the
acting process which informed his transformative performances.
Viola Davis, Denzel Washington, Spike Lee, George C.
Wolfe, Branford Marsalis, Phylicia Rashad and more take us behind the scenes
to explore Boseman's extraordinary commitment to his craft.
Self, played by Danai Gurira.
Self, played by Brian Helgeland.
Self, played by Reginald Hudlin.
Self, played by Aakomon Jones.
Self, played by Woodie King Jr..
Self, played by Spike Lee.
Chadwick Aaron Boseman (; November 29, 1976 – August 28,
2020) was an American actor and playwright.
Through his two-decade career, he appeared in a number of projects spanning both blockbuster and independent films, and received various accolades, including a
Golden Globe Award, a Screen Actors Guild Award, and a Primetime Emmy Award, in addition to nominations for an Academy Award and a BAFTA Award.
Born in South Carolina, Boseman studied directing at Howard
University and began his career in theatre.
Boseman won a Drama League Directing Fellowship and an acting AUDELCO, along with
receiving a Jeff Award nomination for his 2005 play Deep Azure.
Transitioning to the screen, his first major role was as a series regular on the NBC drama Persons Unknown
(2010) and he landed his breakthrough role as baseball player Jackie Robinson in 42 (2013).
He continued to portray historical figures, starring as singer James Brown in
Get on Up (2014) and as Thurgood Marshall in Marshall (2017).
Boseman achieved international fame for playing the Marvel Comics superhero T'Challa
(Black Panther) in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU) from 2016 to 2019.
He appeared in four MCU films, including an eponymous 2018 film.
As the first Black actor to headline an MCU film, he
was also named in the 2018 Time 100.
Boseman's final performance as the character in the
Disney+ anthology series What If...?
(2021) earned him a posthumous Primetime Emmy Award for
Outstanding Character Voice-Over Performance.
In 2016, Boseman was diagnosed with colon cancer.
He kept his condition private, continuing to act until
his death from the illness in 2020.
For his final film role, the drama Ma Rainey's Black Bottom (2020), he received the Golden Globe and SAG
Awards for Best Actor, along with a posthumous nomination for the Oscar in the same category.